Contact

venkateshwarlu.sonnathi@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ venkateshwarlu-sonathi-51b66b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Project Management Analytics Business Analytics

Certifications

Introduction to Big Data
Hadoop Platform and Application
Framework

Publications

Transition Probability Estimation Using Repeated Sampling from a Fitted Mixed Model

Transition Probability Estimation Using Repeated Sampling from a Fitted Mixed Model

A De Novo Economic Model to Assess the Cost and Quality of Life Consequences of an Intervention for Levodopa Induced Dyskinesia Amongst Patients with Parkinson's Disease

How Does Uncertainty Around Costs And Effects Relate To Uncertainty Around Cost-Effectiveness?

How Does Uncertainty Around Costs And Effects Relate To Uncertainty Around Cost-Effectiveness?

venkateshwarlu sonathi

Vice President - Analytics & Al at SPi Global Chennai

Summary

I am a data science enthusiast and built and led data science teams across multiple industries.

I have had the wonderful experience of working and training many budding data scientists in different aspects of data science and working with them on building solutions to varied business problems like Fraud detection, Marketing, Match making, Operations and Credit Risk.

I have experienced decisions based on data and sound methodology having a higher chance of success than the ones based on charismatic communication and Powerpoint.

Experience

SPi Global

Vice President - Analytics & Al August 2018 - Present (2 years 1 month)

Chennai Area, India

I head a team that develops machine learning based products and augmentation tools for enhancing productivity.

OpenMinds consulting

Director

February 2017 - Present (3 years 7 months)

Chennai Area, India

Accomplished professionals in Data Analytics and Consumer behavior, we provide data insights to answer the 4 fundamental business questions of what is ?

What if?

How much?

How likely?

check us out at www.openmindsconsult.com

Matrimony.com Limited
Vice President - Decision Sciences

January 2016 - January 2017 (1 year 1 month) Chennai

I work with the CEO and business heads to identify opportunities and data driven insights to drive business growth. My team developed the Match making algorithm and identifies product changes to better the customer experience.

Novartis

4 years 2 months

Associate Director, ClinOps insights and Innovations August 2014 - January 2016 (1 year 6 months)

Manage a team of data scientists who solve business problems using a variety of data analytic techniques.

Areas: Machine learning, Text analytics, Linear programming, Visulaisation

Group Head- Economic Modeling
December 2011 - July 2014 (2 years 8 months)

I lead the Economic modeling team based out of Hyderabad. We develop economic models for new molecules which are in pipeline

NMIMS Bangalore Adjunct Faculty January 2015 - April 2015 (4 months) Bangalore

I designed and Conducted a course in Pharma analytics for 2nd year MBA students. I received the highest rating in the analytics stream.

Novartis Healthcare Private Ltd.

Group Head: Marketing Science

September 2008 - November 2011 (3 years 3 months)

Build and Manage a team which would develop high end analytical tools for the US Pharma business. Some examples are

- o Promotion response modeling (ongoing promotions)
- o Promotion tracking and ROI estimation of one-time promotions)
- o Advanced analytics for targeting and segmentation
- o Manage and enhance promotion tracking tools
- o Help develop Promotion Mix models and Portfolio Optimizers to optimise allocation of Marketing Resources

Cognizant Technology Solutions

2 years 2 months

Deputy General Manager

November 2007 - September 2008 (11 months)

Liase with third party analytics vendors. Evaluate the products and suggest improvements

Develop Fraud detection products for a Healthcare client.

Idenitfy fraud patterns using data driven techniques, prior knowledge of Fraud in other domains.

Pitch Analytics to prospective clients

Train people in SAS

Manager- Analytics services

August 2006 - October 2007 (1 year 3 months)

Liase with third party analytics vendors for developing fraud detection tools for a health care client.

Develop Fraud detection products for a Healthcare client.

Idenitfy fraud patterns using data driven techniques, prior knowledge of Fraud in other domains.

Citibank

Manager

June 2003 - August 2006 (3 years 3 months)

Developed response scorecards for acquisition and cross sell campaigns for various financial products

Developed optimisation frameworks involving measurement of price elasticity for Balance transfers and Loans

Developed customer segmentation frameworks for wealth management services

American Express

Business Analyst- Credit Abuse

April 2002 - June 2003 (1 year 3 months)

Identify Innovative ways of credit card fraud which the card members are indulging in to defraud the bank.

It was my intoduction to the field of analytics and was a pretty interesting stint.

Reckitt Benckiser Production 1998 - 1999 (1 year)

Education

Indian Institute of Management, Calcutta PGDCM, Finance, Systems · (2000 - 2002)

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras B-Tech, Chemical Engineering (1994 - 1998)

Atomic Energy Central School
Plus2, Junior High/Intermediate/Middle School Education and
Teaching · (1990 - 1994)